<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<page>
	<content-type>/page/techsupportdetailEn</content-type>
	<display-template>/templates/web/page/technical-assis-detail.ftl</display-template>
	<no-template-required/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>6fae</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>6faef340-2839-96cf-9143-0fd910766d95</objectId>
	<file-name>index.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name>support-for-blue-ear-disease</folder-name>
	<internal-name>Coccidiosis in pigs</internal-name>
	<diseaseName_s>Coccidiosis in pigs</diseaseName_s>
	<placeInNav>false</placeInNav>
	<orderDefault_f>-1</orderDefault_f>
	<section_o item-list="true">	<item datasource="section" inline="true">	<key>48c5ba73-f418-a573-9cc9-75ba11aff30f</key>
	<value>Slide</value>
<component id="48c5ba73-f418-a573-9cc9-75ba11aff30f">
	<content-type>/component/headerslide</content-type>
	<display-template>/templates/web/slide.ftl</display-template>
	<no-template-required/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>48c5</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>48c5ba73-f418-a573-9cc9-75ba11aff30f</objectId>
	<slide_o item-list="true">	<item>	<image_s>/static-assets/images/slides/Layer 193.png</image_s>
	</item></slide_o>
	<file-name>48c5ba73-f418-a573-9cc9-75ba11aff30f.xml</file-name>
	<internal-name>Slide</internal-name>
	<createdDate>2020-07-13T08:01:20.081Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2020-07-13T08:01:20.081Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-07-13T08:01:20.081Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-07-13T08:01:20.081Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>
	</item></section_o>
	<diseaseContent_html>&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Coccidiosis caused by the parasite Isospora suis, which occurs in pigs of all ages but is most common in piglets following the mother, concentrated in pigs under 2 weeks of age. The disease is quite common in places where pigs are raised with high density and poor sanitary conditions. There are eight species of Eimeria and one species of Isospora that causes coccidiosis in pigs in North America. Pigs from 5 to 15 days old are usually infected with coccidiosis characterized by I. suis, which causes enteritis and diarrhea. Pasteurellosis is common in newborn piglets. The disease is characterized by fluid or thick diarrhea, often milky white and then yellow and foul-smelling. Piglets may appear symptoms such as weakness, dehydration and stunting; reduce weight gain and piglets may die. Another factor contributing to the increased mortality is that the piglets are always covered with stool due to diarrhea and are always in wet condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Coccidiosis in pigs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The oocytes of coccidiosis are usually excreted with the feces and can be identified by their size, shape and spore-specific characteristics; however, in diagnosis, it must be based on finding parasitic stages through cytological examination or histological examination of the small intestine, as piglets may die before oocyte formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In severely infected animals, histological lesions occur in the colon and ileum characterized by lesions such as atrophy, intestinal villi, hemorrhage and enteritis accompanied by fibrin depending on the stage of the parasite in the cell. epithelial cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The control and prevention by using antiseptic drugs for sows from 2 weeks before farrowing to calving or from birth to weaning has been reported; However, efficacy in the later stages has not been determined. Although sows are considered a source of infection for piglets, this has not been clearly demonstrated. Clean faeces and regular disinfection of cages and breeding equipment between litters significantly reduces the incidence of coccidiosis. Piglets recover badly when coccidiosis infection is highly resistant to re-infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Although less associated with clinical coccidiosis, E debliecki, E neodebliecki, E scabra, and E spinosa species have been found in 1-3 month old pigs with diarrhea. The disease can last 7-10 days for live pigs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Sulfamethazine can be used in drinking water to treat coccidiosis. Coccidiosis control in newborn piglets infected with I. suis is very difficult. The use of coccidiostats against sow feed for a few days or weeks before and after calving was recommended and used in practice, but the results were not stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The use of Amprolium and Monensin was not effective in preventing coccidiosis in piglets in the experiment. A controlled procedure to reduce the number of follicles is recommended, including: cleaning, disinfection and steam cleaning of the breeding facilities. Amprolium supplement (25% type used in feed) at a dose of 10kg / ton of feed, sow this feed a week before farrowing and lasts until the piglet is 3 weeks old, but the results are still not as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Using a single dose of Toltrazuril (20 mg / kg, orally) helps reduce follicle secretion, reduces the incidence of diarrhea, and reduces weight loss in pigs infected with coccidiosis experimentally. Dicalazuril (5mg / kg) is being studied as an anti-coccidiosis drug in piglets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Acare Vietnam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</diseaseContent_html>
	<createdDate>2020-07-13T08:00:36.896Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2020-07-13T08:00:36.896Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-08-05T04:17:49.888Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-08-05T04:17:49.888Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
	<technicalAssistance_o>	<item>	<key>benh-gia-suc-gia-cam</key>
	<value_smv>Poultry disease</value_smv>
	</item></technicalAssistance_o>
	<parentURL_s>/en/technical-assistance/group-sick/poultry-disease/index</parentURL_s>
	<createdDate_dt_dt>2020-08-05T04:17:50.000Z</createdDate_dt_dt>
	<createdDate_dt_dt_tz>Asia/Ho_Chi_Minh</createdDate_dt_dt_tz>
</page>